<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on tess&#39; diary</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on tess&#39; diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 18:53:13 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The books I read in September</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/september-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 18:53:13 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/september-books/</guid>
      <description>The Seep1 by Chana Porter — 🌕🌕🌕🌕🌗:&#xA;The Seep was an incredibly novel, insightful, and crucially empathetic vision of an &amp;ldquo;alien invasion&amp;rdquo;, and through this novum so many aspects of life and loss. After the main character, Trina FastHorse Goldberg-Oneka&amp;rsquo;s, wife Deeba decides that she wishes to be reborn as a child (and Trina declines to raise her), the book follows her as she journeys on an &amp;ldquo;unexpected quest&amp;rdquo; to try rescue a lost boy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Existing Outside Normative Perceptions of Gender in The Bell Jar (and A Birthday Present [and A Birthday Present for Sylvia Plath])</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-bell-jar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-bell-jar/</guid>
      <description>When I am quiet at my cooking I feel it looking, I feel it thinking&#xA;&amp;lsquo;Is this the one I am too appear for, Is this the elect one, the one with black eye-pits and a scar?&#xA;Sylvia Plath - A Birthday Present&#xA;In reading The Bell Jar and then A Birthday Present - which was written approx. a year after the first completed manuscript of The Bell Jar - there seems at least to me to be this thematic through line of the veil, the border, or indeed the titular bell jar.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The books I read in August</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/august-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 09:10:45 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/august-books/</guid>
      <description>The Oleander Sword1 by Tasha Suri — 🌕🌕🌕🌕🌗:&#xA;This month was somewhat of an attempt at finishing off a few series that I&amp;rsquo;ve had on the backburner for a while, and starting that off The Oleander Sword (sequel to The Jasmine Throne) did not disappoint at all. Almost every aspect of this book built amazingly off the first, the pacing was great and didn&amp;rsquo;t lose any tension despite being a &amp;ldquo;middle book&amp;rdquo; of a trilogy, and the changes in the ways in which the Ahiranyi people viewed the Yaksa (without giving any major spoilers) set up some amazing tension for the final book.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yellowface</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/yellowface/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 22:43:48 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/yellowface/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of discourse around this book, which I think considering its content and focus really highlights how well written it is - Yellowface is an amazing book and I think a huge part of that is how it forces its audience into engaging with its themes. Kuang is not at all passive in her representation of themes throughout the book through the ways in which June is blatantly racist from the first chapter to the last, the perversive voyeurism of the omnipresent &amp;ldquo;audience&amp;rdquo; and the relationship to authorial identity and &amp;ldquo;honesty&amp;rdquo;, and the ways in which the publishing industry works to further oppress marginalised writers and audiences.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Living on Stolen Land</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/living-on-stolen-land/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 22:42:55 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/living-on-stolen-land/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It Lives!!!!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/live/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 22:22:17 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/live/</guid>
      <description>Oml the website is finally live!!&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m really not great at this whole coding thing so god it took me a lot of googling but we finally got here and I have a real website! I hit a bit of a writing block while I tried to get this to work hence the burst of posts written like two weeks ago and then nothing until now, but I&amp;rsquo;ve got more to write about books and other stuff over the next few days!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I find another book written before the 1960s and shock myself by enjoying it</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-enchanted-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-enchanted-april/</guid>
      <description>Every time I read a book written before like the 1960s I am kind of always surprised by how funny they are and that probably says a lot about me as a person. Especially this and Emma (by Jane Austen) are both some of the funniest books I have read in such a long time that at this point I probably shouldn&#39;t be shocked. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a huge number of particularly deep or analyticaly thoughts about the book, but it was hilariously and beautifully written - I adored the four main characters who were all deeply interesting and unique, especially of these Lotte and Lady Charlotte were probably my two favourite characters in the text.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Autobiography of Malcolm x</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-autobiography-of-malcolm-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 14:01:58 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-autobiography-of-malcolm-x/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Each day I live as if I am already dead, and I tell you what I would like for you to do. When I am dead - I say it that way because of the things I know, I do not expect to live long enough to read this book in its finished form - I want you to watch and see if I&amp;rsquo;m not right in what I say: that the white man, in his press, is going to identify me with &amp;lsquo;hate&amp;rsquo;&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;A Magical Girl Retires&#39; as a Reformation of the Magical Girl Genre</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-magical-girl-retires/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 14:01:58 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-magical-girl-retires/</guid>
      <description>To anyone thinking if they should read this (I vote yes), go read the synopsis, it perfectly conveys the what and why of reading this. In fact, if you want you could put this down (my writing is a lot worse than Seolyeon&amp;rsquo;s, and Anton Hur&amp;rsquo;s translation) and go finish the book first - it&amp;rsquo;s quite short.&#xA;A brief note, I&amp;rsquo;m not the most into the magical girl genre as a whole really, I&amp;rsquo;d probably consider myself more involved than like an average person but considering I write a bit here about the genre&amp;rsquo;s history I want to preface that I might be off on some of these points.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dawnhounds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-dawnhounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-dawnhounds/</guid>
      <description>Just full spoilers in this one, it&amp;rsquo;s too hard to talk about the world without them. This is also a book that my thoughts about will definitely likely change once the sequel comes out - there was a lot of time spent on worldbuilding, mystery, and characterisation that was done really interestingly but didn&amp;rsquo;t pay out in this book and I&amp;rsquo;m not yet certain if I enjoyed that fully or not.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Goode Governor</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-goode-governor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-goode-governor/</guid>
      <description>One of many queer romance novels I&amp;rsquo;ve read recently, but the one I felt like writing about, The Goode Governor (awful name aside like come on) actually surprised me a lot. Centrally in portraying two highly intelligent and motivated queer women which is something that really I don&amp;rsquo;t see much in any romance novels. Reflecting on this, it feels like a lot of the time there is one smart/motivated character in the couple and the other it there to play a foil to them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Straight Mind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-straight-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-straight-mind/</guid>
      <description>Being completely upfront here this is not going to be the most detailed reflection on Wittig&amp;rsquo;s essays, it took me a bit to finish this whole collection and I didn&amp;rsquo;t think to make notes or start this diary until I was a few months past finishing the earlier ones. Unfortunately, as well, the later essays in the collection did lose me somewhat as they begin to discuss a lot more of the literary craft and specifically with reference to some other authors at the time as well as Wittig&amp;rsquo;s own work in a way that I just did not have the background to understand.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here Comes the Sun; Internalised homophobia, rural culture and the environment in Sunburn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sunburn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sunburn/</guid>
      <description>The third book which I&amp;rsquo;ve rated 10/10 with sun in its title (see: She Who Became the Sun, Klara and the Sun); Sunburn is a heart wrenching exploration of childhood and early adulthood in a deeply traditional, rural Irish upbringing. There is so much to talk about from this book and I adored it deeply, but something about it just made me really want to write about the way it uses the environment.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
