<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiction on tess&#39; diary</title>
    <link>https://tes-saract.github.io/tags/fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fiction on tess&#39; diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tes-saract.github.io/tags/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Enchanted April</title>
      <link>https://tes-saract.github.io/posts/the-enchanted-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tes-saract.github.io/posts/the-enchanted-april/</guid>
      <description>Every time I read a book written before the 20th century I am kind of always surprised by how funny they are and that probably says a lot about me as a person. Especially this and Emma (by Jane Austen) are both some of the funniest books I have read in such a long time that at this point I probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be shocked.&#xA;I don&amp;rsquo;t have a huge number of thoughts about the book, but it was hilariously and beautifully written - I adored the four main characters who were all deeply interesting and unique, especially of these Lotte and Lady Charlotte were probably my two favourite characters in the text.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Magical Girl Retires</title>
      <link>https://tes-saract.github.io/posts/a-magical-girl-retires/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 14:01:58 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tes-saract.github.io/posts/a-magical-girl-retires/</guid>
      <description>To anyone thinking if they should read this (I vote yes), go read the synopsis, it perfectly conveys the what and why of reading this. In fact, if you want you could put this down (my writing is a lot worse than Seolyeon&amp;rsquo;s, and Anton Hur&amp;rsquo;s translation) and go finish AMGR first - it&amp;rsquo;s quite short.&#xA;A brief note, I&amp;rsquo;m not the most into the magical girl genre as a whole really, I&amp;rsquo;d probably consider myself more involved than like an average person but considering I write a bit here about the genre&amp;rsquo;s history I want to preface that I might be off on some of these points.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Goode Governor</title>
      <link>https://tes-saract.github.io/posts/the-goode-governor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tes-saract.github.io/posts/the-goode-governor/</guid>
      <description>One of many queer romance novels I&amp;rsquo;ve read recently, but the one I felt like writing about, The Goode Governor (awful name aside like come on) actually surprised me a lot. Centrally in portraying two highly intelligent and motivated queer women which is something that really I don&amp;rsquo;t see much in any romance novels. Reflecting on this, it feels like a lot of the time there is one smart/motivated character in the couple and the other it there to play a foil to them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunburn</title>
      <link>https://tes-saract.github.io/posts/sunburn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tes-saract.github.io/posts/sunburn/</guid>
      <description>From start to finish, the environment in Sunburn is perhaps more of an expression and representation of Lucy&amp;rsquo;s feelings and emotions than anything else we see from her. And this is not to say that we do not get a deep exploration of her thoughts and feelings throughout the text, but rather that the imagery of her rural environment, especially the titular sun, is so importantly a part of her thoughts and feelings that it is impossible to separate the two.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
