<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiction on tess&#39; diary</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fiction on tess&#39; diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I find another book written before the 1960s and shock myself by enjoying it</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-enchanted-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-enchanted-april/</guid>
      <description>Every time I read a book written before like the 1960s I am kind of always surprised by how funny they are and that probably says a lot about me as a person. Especially this and Emma (by Jane Austen) are both some of the funniest books I have read in such a long time that at this point I probably shouldn&#39;t be shocked. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a huge number of particularly deep or analyticaly thoughts about the book, but it was hilariously and beautifully written - I adored the four main characters who were all deeply interesting and unique, especially of these Lotte and Lady Charlotte were probably my two favourite characters in the text.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#39;A Magical Girl Retires&#39; as a Reformation of the Magical Girl Genre</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-magical-girl-retires/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 14:01:58 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/a-magical-girl-retires/</guid>
      <description>To anyone thinking if they should read this (I vote yes), go read the synopsis, it perfectly conveys the what and why of reading this. In fact, if you want you could put this down (my writing is a lot worse than Seolyeon&amp;rsquo;s, and Anton Hur&amp;rsquo;s translation) and go finish the book first - it&amp;rsquo;s quite short.&#xA;A brief note, I&amp;rsquo;m not the most into the magical girl genre as a whole really, I&amp;rsquo;d probably consider myself more involved than like an average person but considering I write a bit here about the genre&amp;rsquo;s history I want to preface that I might be off on some of these points.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Here Comes the Sun; Internalised homophobia, rural culture and the environment in Sunburn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/sunburn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/sunburn/</guid>
      <description>The third book which I&amp;rsquo;ve rated 10/10 with sun in its title (see: She Who Became the Sun, Klara and the Sun); Sunburn is a heart wrenching exploration of childhood and early adulthood in a deeply traditional, rural Irish upbringing. There is so much to talk about from this book and I adored it deeply, but something about it just made me really want to write about the way it uses the environment.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
